Art Collins Papers ARC.0001
Library and Archives
- Series IV: Audiovisual Materials [RESTRICTED], Bulk, 1980-1998; 1967-1998, undated
  Series IV: Audiovisual Materials spans from 1967 to 1998 and includes some undated material. The bulk of the subseries dates between 1980 to 1998. The series is divided into four subseries based on format: ¾-inch videocassettes, VHS videocassettes, audiocassettes, and miscellaneous formats. The materials are primarily related to Collins’ clients, but other artists in the industry are included as well. Within the subseries, items are arranged alphabetically by artist, then alphabetically by content where applicable, except in Subseries 4, where items are arranged by format. Some materials are stored separately or out of sequence due to content, size, or condition concerns.
  - Subseries 1: 3/4-inch Videocassettes [RESTRICTED], 1980-1993, undated
    The audiovisual materials in this subseries are on defunct media and, therefore, are RESTRICTED. Access copies of these materials will have to be created prior to use. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit to ensure access to these materials is available.
    Subseries 1: 3/4-inch videocassettes spans the years 1980 to 1993 with some undated material, and consists of fourteen 3/4-inch videocassettes. The materials are primarily related to Collins’ clients, notably, Iggy Pop, but other artists are included, such as Jerry Lee Lewis and Little Richard. Within the subseries, items are arranged alphabetically by artist, then alphabetically by content where applicable.
    - 13 Engines, “More”, 1993 April 12 (Box 24, Cassette 1)
    - Dead Boys, Martin Abrams Films Inc., 1980 March 7 (Box 24, Cassette 2)
    - Franken and Davis, Late Night with David Letterman, 1983 March 17 (Box 24, Cassette 3)
    - Lewis, Jerry Lee, Jerry Lee Lewis: Portrait of a Legend, 1981 June 8 (Box 24, Cassette 4)
    - Little Richard, Little Richard: Portrait of a Legend, 1981 June 9 (Box 24, Cassette 5)
    - Nugent, Ted, "Scream Dream / Wango Tango," "Land of Thousand Dancers," "Heads Will Roll", 1982 June 7 (Box 24, Cassette 6)
    - Pop, Iggy
      - "Beside You", undated (Box 24, Cassette 7)
      - “Cold Metal”, undated (Box 24, Cassette 8)
      - "Cry for Love" (final edit), 1986 September (Box 25, Cassette 1)
      - Untitled, undated (Box 25, Cassette 2-4)
    - Robinson, Smokey, Smokey Robinson: Portrait of a Legend, 1981 June 1 (Box 25, Cassette 5)
    - Rogers, Kenny, Kenny Rogers: Portrait of a Legend, 1981 July 13 (Box 25, Cassette 6)
    - White Zombie, " Black Sunshine", 1992 August 10 (Box 25, Cassette 7)
    - Wonder, Stevie, Stevie Wonder: Portrait of a Legend, 1981 June 2 (Box 25, Cassette 8)
  - Subseries 2: VHS Videocassettes [RESTRICTED], Bulk, 1980-1998; 1967-1998, undated
    Subseries 2: VHS videocassettes spans the years 1967 to 1998 and includes some undated material. The bulk of the subseries dates between 1980 and 1998. The subseries consists of 97 VHS videocassettes. The materials are primarily related to the Rolling Stones and Collins' client Iggy Pop, but other artists in the industry are included as well, such as Nirvana and Neil Young. Within the subseries, items are arranged alphabetically by artist, then alphabetically by content where applicable. Videocassettes that include more than one program will be listed more than once in the Collection Inventory.
    The condition of these materials has not yet been determined for playback purposes. Access copies of these materials may have to be created prior to use. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit to ensure access to these materials is available.
    - Crosby, Stills, Nash and Young, Live at Wembley Arena and Winterland Ballroom, 1974 (Box 26, Cassette 1)
    - Hendrix, Jimi, live at Woodstock and Dick Cavett Show, 1967-1969 (Box 26, Cassette 2)
    - Jagger, Mick
      - "I Want My MTV" ad spots, 1982 June 22 (Box 26, Cassette 3)
      - Interview (NBC), undated (Box 26, Cassette 4)
      - “Private Reel,” unedited, undated (Box 26, Cassette 5)
      - “Private Reel, Part 1," Friday night Videos (NBC), undated (Box 26, Cassette 6)
      - “Private Reel, Part 2,” Friday night Videos (NBC), undated (Box 26, Cassette 7)
      - "Speaks to WEA and EMI Records", 1981 July (Box 26, Cassette 8)
    - Mitchell, Joni, PBS American Masters Series, undated (Box 26, Cassette 9)
    - Morrison, Van, Live at the Orphanage and Live in London, 1972-1973 (Box 26, Cassette 10)
    - Nirvana Unplugged, 1993 (Box 26, Cassette 11)
    - Pop, Iggy
      - 7 track compilation, undated (Box 26, Cassette 12)
      - 120 Minutes, undated (Box 26, Cassette 13)
      - Adventures of Pete and Pete, "Grounded For Life", 1994 July 26 (Box 26, Cassette 14)
      - "Beside You", 1993 October 22 (Box 26, Cassette 15)
      - "Beside You" (rough cut), 1993 October 14 (Box 26, Cassette 16)
      - "Butt Town", undated (Box 26, Cassette 17)
      - "Candy", 1990 August 20 (Box 26, Cassette 18)
      - Electronic Press Kit, 1998 November 20 (Box 26, Cassette 19)
      - Electronic Press Kit - Naughty Little Doggie, 1997 April 30 (Box 26, Cassette 20)
      - Feile Festival, 1993 October 26 (Box 26, Cassette 21)
      - "Home", 1990 June 28 (Box 26, Cassette 22-23)
      - "Home," "Candy," censorship spot, undated (Box 26, Cassette 24)
      - IggFest, Much Music, 1993 October 7 (Box 26, Cassette 25)
      - "Images 90" censorship segment, undated (Box 26, Cassette 26)
      - Live in Detroit, State Theater, 1996 April 14 (Box 26, Cassette 27)
      - "Living on the Edge of the Night", undated (Box 26, Cassette 28)
      - "Lust For Life", 1996 July 12 (Box 26, Cassette 29)
      - Manson Family, 1990 July 8 (Box 26, Cassette 30)
      - MTV On-Air Promos, "Influences", undated (Box 27, Cassette 1)
      - Much Music, undated (Box 27, Cassette 2)
      - Nulle Part Ailleurs, 1996 February 26 (Box 27, Cassette 3)
      - "Pussy Walk", 1996 March 13 (Box 27, Cassette 4-6)
      - Space Goofs, "Home to Rent #1," "Scouts Night Out," "Bats in the Belfry," Home to Rent #4", undated (Box 27, Cassette 7)
      - "To Belong", undated (Box 27, Cassette 8)
      - Tonight Show, 1994 March 3 (Box 27, Cassette 9)
      - VH1 Fashion Awards, 1998 (Box 27, Cassette 10)
      - Video Reels, "Home," "Butt Town," "Pop-Candy," "Louie Louie," "Wild American," "To Belong", undated (Box 27, Cassette 11)
      - Virgin Records International Presentation, 1995 September 6 (Box 27, Cassette 12)
      - "Wild America", undated (Box 27, Cassette 13)
      - "Wild America" long uncensored version, 1993 August 25 (Box 27, Cassette 14)
      - "Wild America" short version, rough cut, rough audio, 1993 July 30 (Box 27, Cassette 15)
      - "Wild America" UK version, undated (Box 27, Cassette 16)
    - Richards, Keith
      - “Private Reel, Part 1,” unedited, undated (Box 27, Cassette 17)
      - “Private Reel, Part 2,” unedited, undated (Box 27, Cassette 18)
      - and the Expensive Winos, Live at the Hollywood Palladium (promotional copy), December 1988 (Box 27, Cassette 19)
    - Rolling Stone 25: The MTV Special, undated (Box 27, Cassette 20)
    - Rolling Stones
      - 20 song compilation, undated (Box 27, Cassette 21)
      - Cedar Falls, Unidome, 1981 November 20 (Box 27, Cassette 22)
      - Chicago, Illinois, Checkerboard Club jam, 1981 November 22 (Box 27, Cassette 23)
      - Chicago, Illinois, Rosemont Horizon, 1981 November 23-1981 November 24 (Box 27, Cassette 24-25)
      - Cocksucker Blues, 1972 (Box 27, Cassette 26)
      - Early London promos, undated (Box 27, Cassette 27)
      - East Rutherford, New Jersey, Meadowlands Arena, 1981 November 5 (Box 27, Cassette 28)
      - Emotional Rescue, 4 songs, 1980 (Box 27, Cassette 29)
      - German documentary, part one, 1982 (Box 28, Cassette 1)
      - "Harlem Shuffle", 1986 March 4 (Box 28, Cassette 2)
      - Hartford, Connecticut, Civic Center, 1981 November 9-1981 November 10 (Box 28, Cassette 3-4)
      - Houston, Texas, Astro Dome, part two, 1981 October 29 (Box 28, Cassette 5)
      - Ladies and Gentlemen: The Rolling Stones, 1973 (Box 28, Cassette 6)
      - Live at the Carrierdome, Syracuse, New York, 1981 November 27-1981 November 28 (Box 28, Cassette 7-9)
      - Live at the Checkerboard Club, Chicago with Muddy Waters and Buddy Guy, 1981 November 22 (Box 28, Cassette 10)
      - Live at the Los Angeles Forum, part one, 1975 July (Box 28, Cassette 11)
      - Live at the Silverdome, Pontiac, Michigan, part two, 1981 November 30 (Box 28, Cassette 10)
      - Louisville, Kentucky, Freedom Hall, 1981 November 3 (Box 28, Cassette 12)
      - MTV Extra Stones Special, undated (Box 28, Cassette 13)
      - MTV Paris interviews, 1982 July (Box 28, Cassette 14)
      - New Orleans Riverboat Cruise, 1981 December 3 (Box 28, Cassette 3)
      - New York, New York, Madison Square Garden, 1981 November 12-1981 November 13 (Box 28, Cassette 15-16)
      - "One Hit to the Body", 1986 May 15 (Box 28, Cassette 17)
      - Rewind, undated (Box 28, Cassette 18)
      - "She Was Hot" (NBC Edit - cryon at end, show version), 1984 (Box 28, Cassette 19)
      - "She Was Hot" (NBC Edit - no flames / no number at end), 1984 March 1 (Box 28, Cassette 20)
      - "She Was Hot" (original), 1984 February 6 (Box 28, Cassette 21)
      - "She Was Hot" (original - second cut, flames added at end), 1984 February 13 (Box 28, Cassette 22)
      - "Too Much Blood", 1984 June 15 (Box 28, Cassette 23)
      - "Too Much Blood" (first rough cut), 1984 March 29 (Box 28, Cassette 24)
      - "Too Much Blood" (version #2, bad audio), 1984 May 14 (Box 28, Cassette 25)
      - "Too Much Blood" (version #3, approved), 1984 June 14 (Box 28, Cassette 26)
      - St. Louis, Missouri, Checker Dome, 1981 November 19 (Box 28, Cassette 27)
      - St. Paul, Minnesota, Civic Center (partial), 1981 November 21 (Box 28, Cassette 28)
      - Syracuse, New York, Carrierdome, 1981 November 27 (Box 29, Cassette 1)
      - "Time is on My Side" (German promo clip), 1982 (Box 29, Cassette 2-4)
      - Tattoo You 30 second television spot (first rough cut and mouth effects), circa 1981 (Box 29, Cassette 5)
      - "Undercover of the Night" (performance version), 1983 November 29 (Box 29, Cassette 6)
      - Various clips, undated (Box 29, Cassette 7)
    - Various, No Nukes, undated (Box 29, Cassette 8)
    - Virgin Records, America’s Wildest Home Video Contest (1st place winner), undated (Box 29, Cassette 9)
    - Young, Neil, Year of the Horse, 1997 (Box 29, Cassette 10)
  - Subseries 3: Audiocassettes [RESTRICTED], 1978, 1984, undated
    Subseries 3: Audiocassettes spans 1978 and 1984 and includes some undated material. It consists of ten audiocassettes. The materials are primarily related to the Rolling Stones and its members. Within the subseries, items are arranged alphabetically by artist, then alphabetically by content where applicable.
    - Rocket 88, undated (Box 29, Cassette 11)
    - Rocket 88 Live at Montreaux, undated (Box 29, Cassette 12)
    - Rolling Stones
      - JFK Stadium, 1978 (Box 29, Cassette 13-14)
      - "Still in Love With U", undated (Box 29, Cassette 15)
      - Summer Tour, 1978 (Box 29, Cassette 16)
      - Xmas Issue -- Keith's Tape, undated (Box 29, Cassette 17)
    - Stewart, Ian, Ian Stewart-John Picard Band, Dublin Castle, London, England, 1984 January (Box 29, Cassette 18)
    - Stu's Boogie Woogie Bad Boy Blues Collectables, undated (Box 29, Cassette 19)
    - Watts, Charlie, Charlie Watts Blues All-Stars, undated (Box 29, Cassette 20)
  - Subseries 4: Miscellaneous Formats [RESTRICTED], 1976-1982, 1998
    Some of the audiovisual materials in this subseries are on defunct media formats and, therefore, are RESTRICTED. Access copies of these materials will have to be created prior to use. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit to ensure access to these materials is available. Specific restrictions are listed at the item-level.
    Subseries 4: Miscellaneous Formats spans 1976 to 1982 and includes material from 1998. The series consists of one Betacam SP 10-minute videocassette, one 16mm film reel, one 1/4-inch audio tape reel, and two CD-Rs. The materials are primarily related to Collins’ client, Iggy Pop, but other artists in the industry are included, such as Steve Nieve and Muriel Teodori. Within the subseries, items are arranged by format. The 1/2-inch audio tape reel is stored separately from the other material due to size and condition concerns.
    - Betacam SP 10-minute, Iggy Pop, electronic press kit [RESTRICTED], 1998 November 18 (Box 29, Cassette 21)
      This audiovisual materials is on a defunct media format and, therefore, is RESTRICTED. An access copy of this item will have to be created prior to use. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit to ensure access to these materials is available.
    - 16mm film, Don Harrison Band, Lion Days with contract [RESTRICTIONS], 1976 May 18 (Box 29, Reel 1, Folder 1)
    - 1/4-inch audio tape reel, Silver Condor, "I Stand Accused," "Dear Abby" [RESTRICTIONS], 1982 November 17 (Reel 1)
    - CD-R, Steve Nieve and Muriel Teodori, introduction to Welcome to the Voice, 2000 (Box 29, Disk 1)
    - CD-R, Steve Nieve and Muriel Teodori, Chief of Police, "Troublemaker", 2000 (Box 29, Disk 2)